

# **Shakil Ahmed**

Phone number: (+880) 1761290093 Email address: ahmed.shakil.v3@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shak000/

**Website:** https://sahmedadnan.github.io/Shakil-portfolio/

O Home: House: 18, Road: 15, Nikunja-2, Khilkhet, 1229 Dhaka (Bangladesh)

## **ABOUT ME**

A highly motivated Computer Science graduate with a profound understanding of programming languages and application frameworks. Shakil Ahmed has a strong educational background and enjoys collaborating on Computer Science research. In addition, after completing his further education, he intends to inspire the next generation by contributing to academics in Bangladesh.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### **Master of Science**

American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB) [ 2021 ] Address: 408/1, Kuratoli, Khilkhet , 1229 Dhaka (Bangladesh)

Website: https://www.aiub.edu/

Field(s) of study: Computer Science (Major: Intelligent Systems)

Final grade: 4.00 out of 4.00 - Level in EQF: EQF level 7

**National classification:** Master of Science – **Type of credits:** BD Credit Hours – **Number of credits:** 36 **Thesis:** Attention-Based Bi-LSTM and Sequential LSTM for Describing Video in the Textual Formation.

#### **Bachelor of Science**

American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB) [ 2020 ]

Address: 408/1, Kuratoli, Khilkhet, 1229 Dhaka (Bangladesh)

Website: <a href="https://www.aiub.edu/">https://www.aiub.edu/</a>
Field(s) of study: Computer Science

Final grade: 3.86 out of 4.00 - Level in EQF: EQF level 6

National classification: Bachelor of Science – Type of credits: BD Credit Hours – Number of credits: 130

Thesis: An Observation of Vision Based Underwater Object Detection and Tracking.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Flutter Developer**

Jackal IT [ 01/03/2022 - Current ]

**Skills Gained:** Robust Android/IOS apps development, Clean code architecture, Test cases, Version control systems (Git). **Responsibilities:** 

- Build B2B projects for the company and deploy in play store.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define and deliver new features.

### **Lecturer and Trainer**

Cross-platform Mobile Application Development - Under ICT Division [ 01/08/2021 - 31/01/2022 ]

**Skills Gained:** Teaching, Flutter framework, Dart programming Language, UI design, Firebase database, RestAPI. **Responsibilities:** 

- Supervised 160 students and taught Flutter framework and Dart programming.
- 16 projects were developed by the students under my supervision.

## Teaching Assistant [JAVA Lab]

American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB) [ 01/06/2019 - 31/08/2019 ]

## Responsibilities:

- Helped students who need extra support, Supervision of group projects.
- Assisting with problem solving and the faculty member in lab.

## **RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS**

## **Journal Articles**

[1] **Ahmed, S.**, Saif, A. F. M. S., Hanif, M. I., Shakil, M. M. N., Jaman, M. M., Haque, M. M. U., Shawkat, S. B., Hasan, J., Sonok, B. S., Rahman, F., & Sabbir, H. M. (2021, December 29). Att-BiL-SL: Attention-Based Bi-LSTM and Sequential LSTM for Describing Video in the Textual Formation. *Applied Sciences*, *12*(1), 317. <a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/app12010317">https://doi.org/10.3390/app12010317</a>

[2] Hanif, M. I., **Ahmed, S.**, Akanda, W., & Barman, S. (2020). Anti-Molestation: An IoT based Device for Women's Self-Security System to Avoid Unlawful Activities. *International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications*, *11*(11). <a href="https://doi.org/10.14569/ijacsa.2020.0111188">https://doi.org/10.14569/ijacsa.2020.0111188</a>

#### **Conference Proceedings**

[1] **Ahmed, S.**, Khan, M. F. R., Labib, M. F. A., & Chowdhury, A. E. (2020, February). An Observation of Vision Based Underwater Object Detection and Tracking. 2020 3rd International Conference on Emerging Technologies in Computer Engineering: Machine Learning and Internet of Things (ICETCE). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1109/icetce48199.2020.9091752">https://doi.org/10.1109/icetce48199.2020.9091752</a>

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, Dart, C, C++, C#, Java / Mobile Application Frameworks: Flutter / Machine and Deep Learning Frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-Learn, Pytorch (Basic) / Database: MySQL, Oracle, SQLite, Xampp, Firebase / Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP / Software and Tools: MS Office, Latex (Overleaf), Anaconda, VS Code, Skype / Version Control Systems: Git (GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree)

# **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Bangla

Other language(s):

### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2** 

### **AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS**

## **Academic Awards and Achivements**

- Summa Cum Laude Master of Science [2021].
- Magna Cum Laude Bachelor of Science [2020].
- 3 Dean List Honors Bachelor of Science [2016 2019].
- 65% Tution Fee Waiver Bachelor of Science [2016 2019].
- 1st Runner Up CS-Fest AIUB [2018].

## Certifications

- Python for Everybody Specialization Awarded by Coursera.
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning Awarded by Coursera.
- Natural Language Processing with Python and NLTK Awarded by Udemy.
- Python for Data Science and Data Analysis Masterclass: 2023 Awarded by Udemy.

### **RECOMMENDATIONS**

#### **Assistant Professor**

Name: Dr. Ashraf Uddin Email: dr.ashraf@aiub.edu

Relation: Thesis Supervisor (External)

#### Lecturer

Name: Md. Mazid-Ul-Haque Email: mazid@aiub.edu

Relationship: Thesis Supervisor